<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Nick&#39;s Sports Blog</title>
<link>https://your-website-url.example.com/</link>
<atom:link href="https://your-website-url.example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>I like talking about sports</description>
<generator>quarto-1.8.25</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Is the Pocket Passing Quarterback still Viable?</title>
  <dc:creator>Nick Roth</dc:creator>
  <link>https://your-website-url.example.com/posts/pocket-passing-quarterback-viability/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>Over the last few years the NFL has seen the rise of mobile quarterbacks. The 2010s were highlighted by superstar pocket-passing quarterbacks such as Tom Brady, Peyton Manning and Drew Brees. The 2020’s have brought a new generation of much more mobile quarterbacks that have asserted themselves as the top signal callers in the game, such as Patrick Mahomes, Lamar Jackson, and Josh Allen. This has caused teams to try to step away from the tradition pocket passer and find a mobile QB of their own. Much of this effort is intended to combat the modern day pash rush, that has been improving steadily over the pass decade.</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div>
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://your-website-url.example.com/posts/pocket-passing-quarterback-viability/index_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-2-1.png" class="img-fluid figure-img" width="672"></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>The issue with this philosophy is that mobility does not always mean avoiding sacks. Some of the most mobile quarterbacks such as Jayden Daniels and Jalen Hurts rank amongst the bottom of the league in sacks avoided, where as more traditional pocket passers such as Brock Purdy and Bo Nix rank highly in this category.</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div>
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://your-website-url.example.com/posts/pocket-passing-quarterback-viability/index_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-3-1.png" class="img-fluid figure-img" width="672"></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>However, the players that rank highest in this category are Josh Allen. Jordan Love and Lamar Jackson, who are all very mobile quarterbacks. The conclusion that can be drawn from this is that although mobility is affective for avoiding sacks, it simply isn’t everything. The best way to combat this as a quarterback is to make sure to be decisive and get rid of the ball quickly. Pocket passing quarterbacks such as Joe Burrow and Baker Mayfield are amongst the most successful quarterbacks because of this.</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">
<div>
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://your-website-url.example.com/posts/pocket-passing-quarterback-viability/index_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-4-1.png" class="img-fluid figure-img" width="672"></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>There is no denying that having a mobile quarterback does not provide advantages to their teams. But with good decision making (and a half decent offensive line), teams can still be successful with a pocket passing quarterback.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>quarterback</category>
  <category>football</category>
  <category>scrambling</category>
  <guid>https://your-website-url.example.com/posts/pocket-passing-quarterback-viability/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://your-website-url.example.com/posts/pocket-passing-quarterback-viability/image.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
